MOCHAMAD REZA INDRAPERDANA Data Engineer

Jakarta, Indonesia | Phone: 081381701370 | Email: reza.indra24@gmail.com | Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/mochrezai

SUMMARY

I am quite enthusiastic about data. Familiar and proficient with R and python language, regression, classification, and data visualization. A person who is keen and interested in learning about new technologies, particularly in the data area. I am an analytical thinker in a systematic way, attention to detail, collaboration, and communication skills.possess experience analyzing around three million pieces of data each week, working with different teams, actively assisting businesses with various projects.

EXPERIENCE

PT. LAWENCON INTERNASIONAL (BRI PROJECTS)

Jakarta, Indonesia

Data Engineer

July 2023 – Present

- Build and maintain Report BRI's Clients (BAZNAS, PGN, BPJSTK, KAI, etc).
- Build Reconciliation between Data BRI's Clients and Data Master BRI using python.
- Build Parameter for Settlement.
- Pull data from server staging using job python.
- Collect Data MT940 using SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS).
- Build Job python to get responses from BRI's middleware services.

REVOU Online

Data Analyst Associate

January 2023 – April 2023

- Redevelop business performance management process by developing a Business Performance (KPI)
 Management Dashboard. There are 3 dashboards (strategic, analytical, and operation dashboard) that have
 different users.
- Conduct different approaches in different segments using customer segmentation analysis to maximize customers.
- Making recommendations for our team's customer segmentation result using funnel analysis.

PT. ASTRA GRAPHIA IT (TELKOMSEL PROJECTS)

Jakarta, Indonesia January 2018 – June 2023

Software Developer & Data Engineer

1-----

TNPS Project

January 2021 – June 2023

Project aims to determine customer satisfaction, then make a report in the form of a dashboard. Here's what I did in this project:

- Analyze about 3 million raw data a week and share it to server Business Intelligence.
- Collect and share raw data to help business teams in daily report.
- Build dashboard, weekly report, and monthly report for stakeholders.
- Embedded visualization of tableau reporting to TNPS.

Project Operation ITBP

October 2019 - December 2020

Departments that focused on business partners, as well as documenting business partner activities into a catalog. Here's what I did in this department:

- Cleansing data from raw sources for customer satisfaction survey.
- Analyze and build visualization from customer satisfaction survey.
- Build SLA and OLA Creator by using office 365 platform (powerapps, sharepoint, ms. flow).
- Build Demand Management Dashboard by using Laravel Framework.
- Build Executive Summary Dashboard by using Laravel Framework.

Project Operation IT VAS Charging

June 2019 – September 2019

The department had a lot of workloads but had few resources, so it needs to be monitored for each employee's work. Here's what I did in this department:

- Build Workload Dashboard by using CodeIgniter Framework.
- Build VAS Timesheet Dashboard by using Codelgniter Framework.

B2BM2M Project

January 2018 - May 2019

Department that focused on developing business to business and machine to machine tools and applications. Here's what I did in this department:

- Enhancement and bug fixing CUG SME Apps, including UAT, SIT, NFT, and release to production server. This application uses Codelgniter Framework.
- Enhancement and bug fixing Web2sms Apps by using Native Php.
- Build registration API for B2b2c Apps by using Java Spring.
- Enhancement and bug fixing B2b Platform, including unit testing. This application uses Yii Framework.

PT. ZAHIR INTERNATIONAL

Jakarta, Indonesia

Software Developer

March 2015 - December 2017

Company was making a new product, namely zahir online. This product was believed to be able to give morecustomers. To help with that, here's what I did:

- Develop customer information about subdomains and invoices using Laravel Framework.
- Develop payment gateway with API from third party.
- Develop admin dashboard for internal company information using Laravel Framework.

PT. INNOVATE MAS INDONESIA

Software Developer

Jakarta, Indonesia May 2014 – February 2015

The company was creating a customer web selfcare, to facilitate interaction between the company and customers. Tohelp with that, here's what I did:

- Develop customer information interface using Codelgniter Framework.
- Develop customer subscribed package using Codelgniter Framework.
- Develop customer invoice using CodeIgniter Framework.

EDUCATION

REVOU (2022)

Full Stack Data Analytics Program

Online
2022

- Understanding problem statement and business acumen, exploratory data analysis, A/B testing, user segmentation, prediction analysis, and visualization.
- Group Final Project: "World's Life Expectancy" (Best Group)

UNIVERSITAS TELKOM

Bandung, Indonesia 2009 - 2014

Bachelor of Information System

SKILLS

- Python
- SQL Server, MySQL
- Microsoft Excel
- Laravel
- Tableau
- Google Products for Data Analytics
- SQL Server Integration Service (SSIS)

- Communication
- Analytical Thinking
- Attention to Detail
- Collaboration
- Integrity